Hi everyone, I am Pierre and I co-chair the
大家好，我是 Pierre 我也是
Joint W3C/SMPTE Workshop on
此次 W3C/SMPTE Web专业媒体产品
Professional Media Production on the Web. 5-p
联合研讨会的联席主席。 5-p
Today I want to share with you recent advances that
今天我想和大家分享一下最近的进展
make it possible to work with professional media
让任何一个浏览器运行专业媒体
in any web browser... and demonstrate it is actually possible
成为可能... 并证明它实际上是可以播放
to play lossless UHD video, directly from
无损超高清视频， 直接从
an HTTP server, without proxies and without plugins.
一个 HTTP 服务器，没有代理和插件。
But first some background. slide-2
首先阐述一些背景。 slide-2
Once upon a time there was a huge gap
之前在专业内容和网络浏览器之间
between professional content and the web browser.
有一个巨大的问题。
The two used different media formats and codecs.
两者使用不同的媒体格式和编解码器。
The two targeted different qualities of experience.
两者针对了不同的体验质量。
And professional content was primarily on-prem
专业媒体内容主要是在本地
whereas the browser was Internet-first
而浏览器是互联网优先的
… but times have changed. slide-3
……但时代变了。 slide-3
First, the web browser has come
首先网页浏览器
a long way since 2000.
自 2000 年以来走过了很长的道路。
Back then, the web was text
那时，Web 是文本
with the occasional video playing through plugins. 25-p
偶尔会通过插件播放视频。 25-p
Fast forward to today, the web now allows
到今天，Web 现在允许
complex multimedia experiences through standard APIs. 28-p
通过标准 API 实现复杂的多媒体体验。 28-p
Particularly important for professional content,
对于专业媒体内容尤为重要，
WebAssembly now allows C/C++ libraries
WebAssembly 现在允许 C/C++ 库
to be ported directly to the web. 32-p
可以直接移植到 Web 上。 32-p
This makes it possible to use professional media
这使得
formats and codecs that are not
使用 Web 浏览器本身不支持的专业媒体格式和编解码器
natively supported by web browsers. slide-4
成为可能。 slide-4
Second, something that seemed improbable
其次，在10年前似乎不太可能发生的事情
just 10 years ago has happened: studio content
发生了：
is now processed in the public cloud. 40-p
工作室内容现在在公共云中处理。 40-p
This is a stunning reversal for an industry
这是一个行业的惊人逆转，
that was largely based on video tape
对于一个主要基于录像带
and perceived the Internet as the wild west. 44-p
并将互联网视为狂野西部的行业来说。 44-p
There is probably not a single event
这种转变的背后
behind this transition.
可能并不是一件事引起的。
Perhaps it was the disruption in tape supplies
也许是2010年Tōhoku tsunami海啸造成的
caused by the Tōhoku tsunami in 2010,
磁带供应中断
or Netflix’s own experience with
或 Netflix 自己的经历
on-prem database corruption in 2008. 51-p
在2008年本地数据库遭到损坏。 51-p
In the end, the cloud is not only more efficient
最后，云不仅效率更高
but also more secure since fewer humans handle
但也更安全，因为更少的人来处理
the content and fewer copies are made.
内容和较少的副本。
… and all major studios now have moved some of
......现在所有主要工作室都搬走了一些
their workflows to the public cloud. slide-5
他们的工作流到公共云。 slide-5
So I think the time is right for professional
所以我认为现在是专业媒体
media to embrace the web platform.
拥抱 Web 平台的时候了。
My personal epiphany came actually in
我的个人顿悟实际上来自于
the middle of pandemic when I ask myself:
疫情中期，当我问自己：
can UHD lossless video be played
可以在 Web 没有代理的浏览器中
in a web browser without proxies? slide-6
播放超高清无损视频吗？ slide-6
Professional UHD lossless video is different
专业超高清无损视频与
than the typical video supported natively
本地支持的典型视频不同
by web browsers. 68-p
在 Web 浏览器中。 68-p
The images are often sampled at 48-bit per pixel,
图像通常以每像素48位采样，
instead of the typical 24-bit per pixel
而不是典型的每像素24位
for consumer video. 72-p
的消费类视频。 72-p
The images are routinely losslessly compressed
图像通常被无损压缩
using codecs like JPEG 2000, instead of
使用像 JPEG 2000这样的编解码器，而不是
using AV1 or AVC lossy compression.
使用 AV1 或 AVC 有损压缩。
This results in bitrates in Gbps,
结果是以 Gbps 为单位的比特率，
as opposed to Mbps. 78-p
与 Mbps 相对。 78-p
The compressed image is ultimately wrapped
压缩后的图像最终被包装
in file formats like MXF, again different
像 MXF 这样的文件格式，
than the formats used for consumer delivery. slide-7
与用于消费者交付的格式再次不同。 slide-7
The traditional approach to playing
传统的 Web 浏览器中的
professional video in web browsers
专业视频播放方式
has been to transcode the professional video
需要转码专业视频
into a format understood by the web browser. 87-p
转换成网络浏览器可以理解的格式。 87-p
This results in a proxy. 89-p
这结果在代理中。 89-p
For example, starting from
例如，从
a 5 Gbps JPEG 2000 MXF file,
一个 5 Gbps JPEG 2000 MXF 文件，
you might end up with
你可能会得到
a 50 Mbps AVC MP4 file. 94-p
一个 50 Mbps AVC MP4 文件。 94-p
This approach has significant drawbacks:
这种方法有明显的缺点：
there is latency in that conversion,
该转换存在延迟，
and metadata and image fidelity are reduced. slide-8
元数据和图像保真度降低。 slide-8
A no-proxy architecture takes
无代理架构需要
a different approach. 101-p
一种不同的方法。 101-p
In this approach, the professional video
在这种方法中，专业视频
is compressed using JPEG 2000
使用 JPEG 2000 压缩
and wrapped in an MXF file,
并包装在一个 MXF 文件中，
which is stored on an HTTP server. 106-p
它存储在 HTTP 服务器上。 106-p
Using the MXF index table,
使用 MXF 索引表，
the web app can access each
Web 应用程序可以访问每个
individual image frame directly
直接单个图像帧
using standard HTTP byte-range requests. 111-p
使用标准的 HTTP 字节范围请求。 111-p
Depending on the network conditions
视网络情况而定
and the size of each frame,
以及每帧的大小，
the web app will end up reading
Web 应用程序将最终读取
complete or partial frames. 116-p
完整或部分帧。 116-p
Using an open source JPEG 2000 C++ library
使用开源 JPEG 2000 C++ 库
compiled to WebAssembly,
编译为 WebAssembly，
the web app can then decode the partial
然后 Web 应用程序可以解码部分
or complete image frames. 121-p
或完整的图像帧。 121-p
Because frames are encoded using JPEG 2000,
因为帧是使用 JPEG 2000 编码的，
decoding a partial frame will not fail
解码部分帧不会失败
and instead will result in
反而会导致
a decoded image with reduced resolution. slide-9
分辨率降低的解码图像。 slide-9
This ability for a partial read of a frame to result in
这种部分读取帧的能力导致
a lower resolution image is
较低分辨率的图像是
a standard feature of JPEG 2000
JPEG 2000 的标准功能
resolution progressive codestreams. 131-p
分辨率渐进码流。 131-p
In such a codestream low spatial frequency
在这样的码流中，低空间频率
information is stored in the lower bytes
信息存储在低字节中
of the codestream.
的码流。
Whereas the high spatial frequency information
而高空间频率信息
is stored in the higher bytes.
存储在较高的字节中。
As a result, reading a partial frame results
结果，读取部分帧结果
into a lower-resolution decoded image. slide-10-p
转换为较低分辨率的解码图像。 slide-10-p
Here’s a live demo and proof-of-concept of
这是一个无代理架构
the no-proxy architecture,
的样例和概念验证，
which I encourage you to visit directly. 143-p
我鼓励你直接访问。 143-p
The video is lossless UHD content at 48-bits per pixel,
视频是每像素 48 位的无损超高清内容，
which amounts for about 5 Gbps. 146-p
这相当于大约5 Gbps。 146-p
The file is stored on S3
该文件存储在 S3 上
and distributed through CloudFront. 149-p
并通过 CloudFront 分发。 149-p
The quality of the video will depend on your
视频的质量将取决于
available bandwidth, but is unlikely
可用带宽，但不太可能
to be pristine given the bit rate involved. 153-p
考虑到所涉及的比特率是原始的。 153-p
Notice, however, that when the video is paused,
但是请注意，当视频暂停时，
the app can download the full frame,
该应用程序可以下载全帧，
which results in pristine quality. slide-11-p
最后展示了原始的质量。 slide-11-p
This is of course only a proof of concept,
这当然只是一个概念证明，
so much improvement is possible. 160-p
如此多的改进是可能的。 160 人
It however demonstrates that it is possible
然而，它表明
to play back UHD lossless video in the browser
在浏览器中以适应网络条件的方式
in a way that adapts to network conditions,
播放超高清无损视频是可能的，
using standard web APIs and open source libraries,
只使用标准 Web API 和开源库，
without any special web server. slide-12-p
没有任何特殊的网络服务器。 slide-12-p
In summary I really believe the time is right
总之，我相信这是个成熟时机
for professional workflows to
让对于专业媒体的工作流程
embrace the web platform. 170-p
去拥抱 Web 平台。 170-p
The web can support professional codecs and formats
Web 可以支持专业的编解码器和格式
and professional media is moving to the cloud. 173-p
专业媒体正在向云端迁移。 173-p
Some gaps nevertheless remain.
尽管如此，仍然存在一些差距。
For example the web platform
例如 Web 平台
really lacks support for high-dynamic range
确实缺乏对高动态和广色域图像
and wide-color gamut images.
的支持。
And sample and accurate media synchronization
样本和准确的媒体同步
can really be improved.
真的可以改进。
Hopefully these gaps can be filled in time. 181-p
希望这些空白能及时填补。 181-p
Thanks again for listening.
再次感谢收听。
Do not hesitate to contact me. Bye!
欢迎随时与我联系。再见！